<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>minecraft mod &#8211; MineVote &#8211; Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/tag/minecraft-mod/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog</link>
	<description>Minecraft Server Guide</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:30:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Add Mods to a Minecraft Server</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1.16.3 minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazing minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asianhalfsquat mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft mods 1.16.3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft mods 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best new minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool new minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mod showcase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 1.16.3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods pc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top 10 minecraft mods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview If you have been playing&#160;Vanilla Minecraft, or using a premade modpack, it is likely that you have already explored all there is to do. Why not start exploring into customizing your server further? A great way to customize your server is by adding mods. Whether you are adding them to an existing&#160;modpack&#160;or to your ... <a title="How to Add Mods to a Minecraft Server" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/" aria-label="More on How to Add Mods to a Minecraft Server">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pmk3nIK96Os/X_m_o2S7ALI/AAAAAAAAACI/zRz5Khv1-aAnjzoVNoO_UKPkR0V94-0SQCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/novaskin-minecraft-wallpaper%2B%25285%2529.jpeg" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>If you have been playing&nbsp;Vanilla Minecraft, or using a premade modpack, it is likely that you have already explored all there is to do. Why not start exploring into customizing your server further? A great way to customize your server is by adding mods. Whether you are adding them to an existing&nbsp;modpack&nbsp;or to your current Forge setup, adding mods is a great way to open up new possibilities. Mods can be added with just a few steps and we will walk you through each of them so you can build your dream&nbsp;server.</p>



<p>When running a modded server, do not forget that you need to have the mods downloaded on your Minecraft client. This also applies if you are adding additional mods to an already created modpack. In order to run mods on your client, you will need to&nbsp;install Forge client side.</p>



<h2>How to Install Mods on a Minecraft Server</h2>



<p>Downloading mods</p>



<ol><li>You need to get the mods from&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#">CurseForge</a>&nbsp;or the mod authors official site. Doing this ensures that you won’t get corrupted files or viruses.</li><li>Once you decide on a mod you want, click the name to open the mod page.</li><li>Open the Files tab to view the versions. To the right of the version you want, press download. It’s best to download the latest recommended update for your version of Minecraft.</li><li>Head back to the mods page and open the Relations tab. This is very important as these are the mods you need for it to work correctly. If you don’t download the dependencies, the server will not function properly, or at all.</li></ol>



<p>Uploading mods</p>



<ol><li>Make sure that your server is set to Forge under the jar dropdown. You can find a tutorial on changing server versions&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#">here</a>. Note that you need to run forge before you put the mods in, to create the mods folder, and if you do not your mods will be deleted.</li><li>Stop the server.</li><li>To the left of the game panel, click on FTP File Access and go into the mods folder.</li><li>Click on “Upload” then simply drag in the mods you have previously downloaded. Wait for the mods to fully upload before leaving this page.</li><li>When you upload mods, it is highly recommended that you generate a new world to ensure that there is no corruption. You can find our guide on making a new world&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#">here</a>.</li><li>Once they are uploaded, head back to the Game Panel and start the server. Once the server is fully started, you are safe to connect.</li></ol>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>Incorrect Forge version</p>



<p>The mods you have uploaded to the server may not always be compatible with the Forge version we have available from our jar selector. If this is the case, you will need to install the correct version of Forge for your mod manually. We have a tutorial on uploading a custom version of Forge&nbsp;here.</p>



<p>Server is crashing on startup</p>



<p>The&nbsp;server crashing&nbsp;during the startup process can be common on Forge servers if they are not setup correctly. This can be due to multiple issues. Most commonly this is caused by a duplicate mod, missing dependency mods, or incorrect mod versions.</p>



<p>Server is stuck loading</p>



<p>Many times when modifying the server, the server will need to be confirmed before it will fully start. This happens a lot especially when you remove or add mods. Most of the time in console, you will see&nbsp;Missing Mod Id’s errors. All you need to do to resolve this is type /fml confirm in console.</p>



<p>Duplicate Mods<br>You can detect a duplicate mod from console pretty easily. You will see an error that says “Duplicate Mods” with the mod name listed underneath it. Simply go into the FTP File Access, the mods folder, and delete the extra mod.</p>



<p>Missing Dependency<br>To detect if you have a missing dependency mod, head into the console where you will see an error code that reads something similar to The mod nei (Not Enough Items) requires mod [JEI] to be available From this error, we can see that the&nbsp;missing mod&nbsp;is JEI. You will need to add the mod into the server in order for the server to work again.</p>



<p>Incorrect Mod Version<br>Detecting if the mod is the incorrect version is pretty easy. It will almost always display an error stating that it is for a different version of Forge. It will look similar to File jei_1.12.2-4.15.0.268.jar is for an older version of Forge and cannot be loaded. If you have this issue, make sure that the mod you are using&nbsp;has an update&nbsp;for the version of Forge you are running. If it doesn’t, then you won’t be able to use the mod on your server.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[$50 minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[budget minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[custom minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to build a minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to make a minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup a minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup a minecraft server 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft funny moments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft school server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft servers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft skeppy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft survival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft trolling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft youtuber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[server]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports Overview Many times when modifying a server you may experience issues with the&#160;server crashing. These crashes are generally caused by either mods, the world, or the server jar. When a server crashes, it generates a crash report in the FTP File Access. These crash reports break down why the ... <a title="How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/" aria-label="More on How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>&nbsp;How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/7383508844279984698#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CpQiDHwbPrc/X-8DXDpMRkI/AAAAAAAAABk/elJ_fAe3ggcvFL45DjBKCRS3-4gnz5nrACLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/minecraft-1106261_1280.webp" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p><strong><br></strong></p>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>Many times when modifying a server you may experience issues with the&nbsp;server crashing. These crashes are generally caused by either mods, the world, or the server jar. When a server crashes, it generates a crash report in the FTP File Access. These crash reports break down why the server crashes and can help you get a better understanding of what’s wrong and how to fix it. At first look, it may seem confusing but all crash reports are similar and once you know what to look for you will be able to accurately read Minecraft crash reports.</p>



<h2>Understanding a Crash Report</h2>



<p>Where to find the crash reports</p>



<ol><li>Head to your Game Panel and to the left, press FTP File Access and log in.</li><li>Once in FTP File Access, you will see a folder named `crash-reports`. Go ahead and click that. Looking inside of that directory you will notice a file or multiple files.</li><li>Every file is written with the date (2019-08-17) which makes it easy to know when each report was made. When there are several files it’s always best to look at the latest and most recent crash to identify the issue.</li><li>To read the crash report, click the “edit” link to the right of the file.</li></ol>



<p>Reading the Crash Report</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">---- Minecraft Crash Report ----
// Everything's going to plan. No, really, that was supposed to happen.

Time: 1/24/20 7:25 AM
Description: Exception in server tick loop

Missing Mods:
	unknown : need [1.5.2,): have missing

net.minecraftforge.fml.common.MissingModsException: Mod thaumcraft (Thaumcraft) requires [baubles@[1.5.2,)]
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.common.Loader.sortModList(Loader.java:266)
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.common.Loader.loadMods(Loader.java:572)
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.server.FMLServerHandler.beginServerLoading(FMLServerHandler.java:98)
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.common.FMLCommonHandler.onServerStart(FMLCommonHandler.java:333)
	at net.minecraft.server.dedicated.DedicatedServer.func_71197_b(DedicatedServer.java:125)
	at net.minecraft.server.MinecraftServer.run(MinecraftServer.java:486)
	at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:748)
</pre>



<p>This is the top portion of the report where it will have the date, time and stack trace. The stack trace is a report of when a program runs at a certain time in its execution. This will be primarily where we will discover the error that is causing the server or client to crash.<br>It looks like a lot but by looking carefully we can deduce the error by picking certain parts of the stack trace out. In this example, we can tell that a mod is missing due to part of the stack trace saying&nbsp;&#8220;Missing Mods: unknown : need [1.5.2,): have missing&#8221;.&nbsp;If we go down to the next line we can see that it tells&nbsp;&#8220;net.minecraftforge.fml.common.MissingModsException: Mod thaumcraft (Thaumcraft) requires [baubles@[1.5.2,)]&#8221;&nbsp;which translates to the mod Thaumcraft needs the mod Baubles version 1.5.2 in order to run properly.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">A detailed walkthrough of the error, its code path and all known details is as follows:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

-- System Details --
Details:
	Minecraft Version: 1.12.2
	Operating System: Linux (amd64) version 3.10.0-957.27.2.el7.x86_64
	Java Version: 1.8.0_222, Oracle Corporation
	Java VM Version: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (mixed mode), Oracle Corporation
	Memory: 1474787976 bytes (1406 MB) / 2075918336 bytes (1979 MB) up to 2075918336 bytes (1979 MB)
	JVM Flags: 4 total; -Xmx2048M -Xms2048M -XX:+UseConcMarkSweepGC -XX:+CMSClassUnloadingEnabled
	IntCache: cache: 0, tcache: 0, allocated: 0, tallocated: 0
	FML: MCP 9.42 Powered by Forge 14.23.5.2847 5 mods loaded, 5 mods active
	States: 'U' = Unloaded 'L' = Loaded 'C' = Constructed 'H' = Pre-initialized 'I' = Initialized 'J' = Post-initialized 'A' = Available 'D' = Disabled 'E' = Errored

	| State | ID         | Version      | Source                           | Signature |
	|:----- |:---------- |:------------ |:-------------------------------- |:--------- |
	| L     | minecraft  | 1.12.2       | minecraft.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | mcp        | 9.42         | minecraft.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | FML        | 8.0.99.99    | forge1122.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | forge      | 14.23.5.2847 | forge1122.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | thaumcraft | 6.1.BETA26   | Thaumcraft-1.12.2-6.1.BETA26.jar | None      |

	Loaded coremods (and transformers): 
	Profiler Position: N/A (disabled)
	Is Modded: Definitely; Server brand changed to 'fml,forge'
	Type: Dedicated Server (map_server.txt)
</pre>



<p>The second half of the crash report will go over your system details and the states of the mods loading in. This can be very important especially with client-side crashing as you can find our what version of Java they are running, how much ram they have allocated and the versions of the mods to be able to assist them. One of the best tools with crash reports is knowing the States in which a mod loads in. These states are as follows:&nbsp;&#8216;U&#8217; = Unloaded &#8216;L&#8217; = Loaded &#8216;C&#8217; = Constructed &#8216;H&#8217; = Pre-initialized &#8216;I&#8217; = Initialized &#8216;J&#8217; = Post-initialized &#8216;A&#8217; = Available &#8216;D&#8217; = Disabled &#8216;E&#8217; = Errored<br>You can see these states to the left of each mod. In this example, they only made it to the loaded state. So if you have a mod that was UCE that would mean the mod Unloaded, Constructed and than Errored which means there was an error with loading that particular mod causing it to crash so you now know what the exact mod causing the issue is and can look into why it&#8217;s occurring.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>There are hundreds of different reasons that your server may crash, it can be from a world issue, server jar, mods, and far more. As long as you can narrow down what the reason is, the solution should come easier. If you can narrow down it’s a world issue, you can Google the error line to see if there are any solutions or you can restore a backup. With so many different solutions to so many different problems, there isn’t a way to break down each individual error you can get.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
