<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>MineVote &#8211; Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog</link>
	<description>Minecraft Server Guide</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:41:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Netherite in Minecraft: A Guide</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to find netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 nether update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 netherite farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft glitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft how to find netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft how to get netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft nether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft nether update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite armor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite automatic farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite glitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft survival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netherite farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netherite minecraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=53</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netherite Minecraft’s newest update, the&#160;Nether Update&#160;brings forth many additions that revolve around the&#160;Nether. New biomes, mobs, structures, and even a new ore: Netherite! This will be a brief guide on how to obtain and use the ore for your benefit. We’ll go over each thing you can create, and the reasons you would pursue it ... <a title="Netherite in Minecraft: A Guide" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/" aria-label="More on Netherite in Minecraft: A Guide">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/6716079997427016986#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JDJBwtInwFY/X_qGEAvzINI/AAAAAAAAAD0/9qSruyQ6vzIAu5hc-H_zlHoWsf5RAkWtQCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25288%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Netherite</h2>



<p>Minecraft’s newest update, the&nbsp;Nether Update&nbsp;brings forth many additions that revolve around the&nbsp;Nether. New biomes, mobs, structures, and even a new ore: Netherite! This will be a brief guide on how to obtain and use the ore for your benefit. We’ll go over each thing you can create, and the reasons you would pursue it over Diamond.</p>



<h2>How to get Netherite</h2>



<p>You’ll&nbsp;<img alt="Netherite in Nether" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153832/ancient_debris_mc-300x300.jpg">be looking for the ‘Ancient Debris’ block. It spawns only in the Nether, and you’ll need a Diamond Pickaxe. Netherite spawns mostly in the Y-axis of 8-22, but it can spawn less so in 8-119. (Note: Ancient Debris is explosion-proof, so TNT mining is viable!)</p>



<p>Once you mine the block, it’ll drop ‘Netherite Scrap’ which you’ll need four of. After that, you’ll need four gold. Once you’ve gotten those, this is the crafting recipe for a Netherite Ingot:<br><img alt="netherite" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153859/make_netherite_ingot-300x283.png"></p>



<h2>Crafting Netherite Armor and Tools</h2>



<p>To obtain any<img alt="netherite sword" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153900/zs0clhaigpk41-300x282.png">&nbsp;Netherite tool or armor piece, you’ll need a Diamond variant of the item, and one Netherite Ingot. Then, you need to use the Smithing Table. Any item or armor piece will only require one Netherite Ingot to be upgraded into a Netherite item. This will not remove your enchantments.</p>



<p>That’s it. You just place the diamond tool/armor into the first slot, then the Netherite Ingot into the second slot and out comes a Netherite item! Oddly enough, this is currently the Smithing Table’s only use.</p>



<h2>What’s the point?</h2>



<p>You might have thought to yourself “I already have full Diamond Prot IV, why would I need that minuscule upgrade. To that, I would say you really don’t. This is a very difficult ore to obtain and it’s meant for those players that want true endgame gear.<br>With that being said, Netherite Tools and Armor have some benefits. Here’s the list:<br>-Slightly faster mining speed<br>-Increased durability<br>-Weapons do more damage<br>-Higher enchantment value (determines the quality of enchantments)<br>-They float in lava (pretty nifty!)<br>-Higher knockback prevention than Diamond Armor</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>For the&nbsp;<img alt="netherite meme" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153902/EWHDedFXkAANc5L-300x298.jpg">majority of you all, this new armor won’t mean much. In fact, it isn’t even that special. But for the minority out there that love to seek out every special discovery, for the crowd that loves to explore and obtain all that there is to obtain this will be a great addition to Minecraft. Although this will not severely shift the meta of the game, it will make it more interesting for a time. It also looks cool, and that’s always a huge plus! With that said, I’ll see you all next time!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Fix The Ticking Entity Crash in Minecraft Server ?</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-fix-the-ticking-entity-crash-in-minecraft-server/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-fix-the-ticking-entity-crash-in-minecraft-server/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[23 ways to crash minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crash minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crash minecraft with arrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entity 404 in minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny minecraft animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to crash minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft crash fix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft crash fix 1.14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft crash fix 1.15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft crash report 1.14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft crash report mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft i found entity 303]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft monster school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft new animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft pe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft pocket edition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=50</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview A Ticking Entity crash will be caused when some form of data, typically a&#160;mob&#160;or block, in the world becomes corrupted. This will usually be displayed in a crash report as follows:&#160;java.lang.nullpointerexception: ticking entity The corruption that can happen in relation to ticking entities can be so severe that anytime the game attempts to process ... <a title="How To Fix The Ticking Entity Crash in Minecraft Server ?" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-fix-the-ticking-entity-crash-in-minecraft-server/" aria-label="More on How To Fix The Ticking Entity Crash in Minecraft Server ?">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/5104592084804196716#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ddxVJV88NJU/X_qFQeFfuKI/AAAAAAAAADs/DjK7I7KGzuEfbnHua_iBS-USTUGPGDuOwCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25287%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>A Ticking Entity crash will be caused when some form of data, typically a&nbsp;mob&nbsp;or block, in the world becomes corrupted. This will usually be displayed in a crash report as follows:&nbsp;java.lang.nullpointerexception: ticking entity</p>



<p>The corruption that can happen in relation to ticking entities can be so severe that anytime the game attempts to process the ticking entity it will crash. While you can see these crashes in a&nbsp;Vanilla world, you are more likely to come across this when playing a modded world. This is purely due to the fact that mods tend to change major aspects of minecraft and can be seen as a more unstable way to play the game.</p>



<h3>Minecraft Ticks</h3>



<p>Ticks are going to be involved with every game you may play. Ticks can be seen as loops of tasks a game does to synchronize itself. Minecraft runs its game loop at a fixed rate of 20&nbsp;ticks per second. This equates to 1 tick every 0.05 seconds. One good example of ticks is the daylight cycle in Minecraft. Each day is 24,000 ticks. This means 1 day in Minecraft equals 20 minutes in real life. Anything you are doing in game will be put in the same loop to be synchronized with the rest of the world.</p>



<h2>Ticking Block &amp; Ticking World</h2>



<h3>Ticking Block</h3>



<p>A Ticking Block crash is generally the same as a Ticking Entity. The difference with this crash is it is related to a block or Tile Entity specifically and not a mob or npc. This will generally be related to special blocks added from a mod.</p>



<h3>Ticking World</h3>



<p>A Ticking World crash is the most severe of them all. This will occur when the game is able to recognize that there is corruption in the world, but will not be able to give a location. The game will have no idea where the corruption occurred and in some cases this is unfixable.<br>Once you have become subjected to a Ticking Entity crash you will have to remove the data from your world to resolve it. Simply removing your mods will not work in this case. This is due to the corruption already being part of your world. Luckily there are multiple ways you can remove the errored entity from your world. Some fixes might work better than others and it will really depend on the specific crash you are facing.</p>



<p>If you discover that even after removing the errored entity the crashing keeps occurring, you may have a faulty mod. If this is the case it is important to find the specific mod/s that are causing this to be able to fix the crashes in the long run. Unfortunately there is no easy way to do this. We would recommend removing any recent additions of Mods to start. If the crashes continue you may want to start removing mods in batches until the issues stop. This will better help you narrow down which mod exactly is causing the problems.</p>



<h2>How to fix a Ticking Entity</h2>



<p>It is very important to resolve this crash as soon as possible. If the erroring entity is not removed your server may backup your world with the errored entity included. In some cases this could remove your only option to fixing the issue.</p>



<h3>Restore from Backup</h3>



<p>The absolute easiest and most straightforward way to fix the Ticking Entity is by restoring a backup() of your world. At Any Hosting we will automatically set up a backup task when you purchase a server. This task will run once per day and save up to two backups on your server at a time. We have a great guide on the restoration process&nbsp;here.</p>



<h3>Crash Reports</h3>



<p>When the server crashes due to a Ticking Entity the&nbsp;crash report&nbsp;will have very important information that can be used in the removal of the errored entity. The following information will be inside of the crash reports:</p>



<ol><li>Type of entity that caused the crash</li><li>Exact coordinates where the Ticking Entity is located.</li></ol>



<p>Below is an example of what you will typically see in a crash report if you experience a ticking entity crash.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">---- Minecraft Crash Report ----

WARNING: coremods are present:
  llibrary (llibrary-core-1.0.11-1.12.2.jar)
  Quark Plugin (Quark-r1.6-178.jar)
  RandomPatches (randompatches-1.12.2-1.21.0.3.jar)
  OTGCorePlugin (OTG-Core.jar)
  Do not report to Forge! (If you haven't disabled the FoamFix coremod, try disabling it in the config! Note that this bit of text will still appear.) (foamfix-0.10.10-1.12.2.jar)
  IvToolkit (IvToolkit-1.3.3-1.12.jar)
Contact their authors BEFORE contacting forge

// This is a token for 1 free hug. Redeem at your nearest Mojangsta: [~~HUG~~]

Time: 6/9/20 7:55 PM
Description: Ticking entity

java.lang.NoSuchMethodError: mmm.common.entities.mobs.EntityShulkerGhast.isAttacking()Z
	at mmm.common.entities.mobs.EntityShulkerGhast.ShootShulkerBalls(EntityShulkerGhast.java:124)
	at mmm.common.entities.mobs.EntityShulkerGhast.func_70071_h_(EntityShulkerGhast.java:93)
	at net.minecraft.world.World.func_72866_a(World.java:1996)
	at net.minecraft.world.WorldServer.func_72866_a(WorldServer.java:832)
	at net.minecraft.world.World.func_72870_g(World.java:1958)
	at net.minecraft.world.World.func_72939_s(World.java:1762)
	at net.minecraft.world.WorldServer.func_72939_s(WorldServer.java:613)
	at net.minecraft.server.MinecraftServer.func_71190_q(MinecraftServer.java:767)
	at net.minecraft.server.dedicated.DedicatedServer.func_71190_q(DedicatedServer.java:397)
	at net.minecraft.server.MinecraftServer.func_71217_p(MinecraftServer.java:668)
	at net.minecraft.server.MinecraftServer.run(MinecraftServer.java:526)
	at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:748)


A detailed walkthrough of the error, its code path and all known details is as follows:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------</pre>



<p>As you can see the description lets us know this is a Ticking Entity crash. If you look closely you can also see that the entity Shulker Ghast is mentioned. Upon even closer inspection you can see that this is coming from a possible mod called MMM. In this case you can do a quick google search to figure out that this entity has been added by the mod&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/5104592084804196716#">Mutated Mobs Mod</a>.</p>



<h3>Ticking World</h3>



<p>If the description in the crash report shows Ticking World or Exception ticking world you will not be able to find exact coordinates of the errored entity. This is due to the world not knowing where the issue is thus not being able to display coordinates. In these cases, we would just recommend you restore a backup() of your world.</p>



<h3>Ticking Entity</h3>



<p>If you take a look further down in the crash report you will be able to find the exact X, Y, Z Coordinates of the ticking entity. Below is an example of this information.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">A detailed walkthrough of the error, its code path and all known details is as follows:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

-- Head --
Thread: Server thread
Stacktrace:
	at mmm.common.entities.mobs.EntityShulkerGhast.ShootShulkerBalls(EntityShulkerGhast.java:124)
	at mmm.common.entities.mobs.EntityShulkerGhast.func_70071_h_(EntityShulkerGhast.java:93)
	at net.minecraft.world.World.func_72866_a(World.java:1996)
	at net.minecraft.world.WorldServer.func_72866_a(WorldServer.java:832)
	at net.minecraft.world.World.func_72870_g(World.java:1958)

-- Entity being ticked --
Details:
	Entity Type: mmm:shulkerghast (mmm.common.entities.mobs.EntityShulkerGhast)
	Entity ID: 104807
	Entity Name: Shulker Ghast
	Entity's Exact location: 183.54, 51.95, 67.90
	Entity's Block location: World: (183,51,67), Chunk: (at 7,3,3 in 11,4; contains blocks 176,0,64 to 191,255,79), Region: (0,0; contains chunks 0,0 to 31,31, blocks 0,0,0 to 511,255,511)
	Entity's Momentum: -0.15, 0.13, -0.07
	Entity's Passengers: []
	Entity's Vehicle: ~~ERROR~~ NullPointerException: null
Stacktrace:
	at net.minecraft.world.World.func_72939_s(World.java:1762)
	at net.minecraft.world.WorldServer.func_72939_s(WorldServer.java:613)</pre>



<p>In the Entity being ticked section you will find all the important information regarding the errored entity. You can more easily see here that it indeed is a ShulkerGhast from the MMM mod. The exact location of the entity is going to be&nbsp;<code>183.54, 51.95, 67.90</code>.</p>



<h3>Cofh Killall Command to Remove Entity</h3>



<p>If you have the mod&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/5104592084804196716#">CoFH Core</a>&nbsp;you will have access to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/5104592084804196716#">/cofh killall command</a>. This command is an improved version of the default Minecraft kill command. You will not need to be connected to the server to run this command. However the server will need to be able to startup in order for the command to be run.</p>



<p>This command will have the ability to kill all creatures even in unloaded chunks on the server. This is crucial as if the chunk loads that has the ticking entity the server will end up crashing. Although CoFH Core is very common you may not have it installed. It is recommended to add this mod to your server’s&nbsp;mods&nbsp;folder to gain access to this command.</p>



<p>In order to remove all loaded entities of a specific type you can use the following command.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">/cofh killall [type]</pre>



<p>The [type] you will enter is going to be the name or part of the name of the entity type to remove from the server. You can also run without a type that will remove all hostile mobs from the server. If for some reason the type is not working you can force the command to remove ALL loaded entities with this command:&nbsp;<code>/cofh killall *</code></p>



<h3>Teleport to the Mob and Kill it</h3>



<p>This would be the “low tech” way to fix the ticking entity. Using the given coordinates from the crash report you can teleport to the entity and in the split second before the crash attempt to kill it in one hit. We recommend putting yourself into creative mode with /gamemode creative and getting a weapon that could instantly kill the entity.</p>



<p>Once you are in creative mode and have a weapon ready you can run the /teleport command to travel to the entity and start swinging away.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">/teleport X Y Z</pre>



<h3>Forge Mod Loader (DANGER)</h3>



<p>One other way to fix the Ticking Entity would be by enabling certain features within the Forge Modloader.&nbsp;Forge&nbsp;will have two settings that will order Minecraft to remove any mobs or blocks that would cause the server to crash. This method of resolution is completely uncontrollable as forge will be given permission to remove anything and everything it deems necessary. If you have ever watched forge startup in console you will know that it will almost always give warnings or errors about one thing or another. This could cause forge to remove things you do not want it to.</p>



<p>WARNING:&nbsp;If you attempt to use this method, make a backup of your server. We cannot stress how much damage this can do to your world, and the damage cannot be fixed. The only way to undo these changes is to restore a backup made before you turned on these settings in Forge, or by restoring a saved copy of your world.&nbsp;Customer Support&nbsp;can not restore any parts of a world deleted by Forge because of these settings, unless you made a backup beforehand.</p>



<p>To turn on these settings, you must find the file forge.cfg, which is normally located in the config folder in the main directory. Select forge.cfg, and then click the edit button to the right of the file.</p>



<p>Find the word false and change it to true. It’s recommended to only turn on the setting appropriate to what you are trying to fix: If trying to correct a Ticking Entity change the one for removeErrorEntities to true, but leave the removeErroringTileEntities set to false. This will hopefully minimize the side effects.</p>



<p>Start the server up, let it finish running. Then immediately shut the server down, open up forge.cfg and change those settings back to false. Leaving them permanently set to true can have continuous side effects. Place a block, and it instantly disappears, because forge didn’t like it and zapped it out of existence.</p>



<p>Try connecting into your game, and check to make sure everything is okay. If you see entire structures and buildings gone, well, that’s the damage we were talking about. If this happened, restore the backup made before turning on the&nbsp;Forge settings, and try one of the other alternative methods of removing the Ticking Entity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-fix-the-ticking-entity-crash-in-minecraft-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Play Minecraft with Friends ?</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beating minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beating minecraft but my friend tries to stop me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft hunter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft manhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft speedrun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft youtube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream smp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream speedrun minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but lava rises every minute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but water rises every minute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft manhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft survival]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=47</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview For years,&#160;Minecraft&#160;has been known as one of the world’s most popular video games. While many may think that this is due to the expansive features and seemingly endless possibilities in single-player, one of the main reasons is the ability to play Minecraft with your friends – even those who are far away. Minecraft singleplayer ... <a title="How to Play Minecraft with Friends ?" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/" aria-label="More on How to Play Minecraft with Friends ?">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/7556756269990714606#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dzFwHTU702s/X_qEH3X9RiI/AAAAAAAAADg/pYERSAVHTSg1lIt78REhmaOrQx8g-w_twCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25286%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>For years,&nbsp;Minecraft&nbsp;has been known as one of the world’s most popular video games. While many may think that this is due to the expansive features and seemingly endless possibilities in single-player, one of the main reasons is the ability to play Minecraft with your friends – even those who are far away.</p>



<p>Minecraft singleplayer is great for sure, however, one can really expand their gameplay experience simply by playing multiplayer with others. There are many ways to play with friends, including LAN servers which allow you to connect with players who are on the same internet as you, Realms which allow you to play across the globe, and servers which is by far the most popular option as it allows you to play modded Minecraft with your friends. You may be wondering how you can play Minecraft online and which option is best for you. That is why in this guide we’ll be breaking down the different ways to connect and play together.</p>



<h2>How to Play Minecraft with Friends on PC</h2>



<h3>LAN World</h3>



<p>In Minecraft, you have the ability to connect with friends through LAN. This will be accessible only to others within your local network. For example, if your friend is over at your house and connected to your wifi, you can create a LAN world to join.</p>



<p>How to make a LAN world</p>



<ol><li>Open up Minecraft, and join your single-player world.</li><li>Press the escape key to open up your Game Menu.</li><li>Press “Open to LAN”, then select if you want to allow cheats and what game mode you want the other users to have, then press “Start LAN World”.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a LAN world</p>



<ol><li>In Minecraft, click on the “Multiplayer” tab.</li><li>Scroll to the bottom of the list, you should see a message that says “Scanning for games on your local network”.</li><li>Once it finds the world, you will see a listing named “LAN World” with your friends username and the world name under it.</li><li>Double click it to join, or select it and press “Join Server”.</li></ol>



<h3>Minecraft Server</h3>



<p>Owning a Minecraft server is one of the best ways for you and your friends to connect with each other through Minecraft. Having your own server stands on top of the other options for a few reasons: You can set it to any version of Minecraft, you can modify it past Vanilla, and servers don’t cap the number of players who can join (of course, you would need a powerful server depending on the number of players you want online.) Playing Minecraft Java Edition with friends on a modded server is one of the most flexible, and fun, ways to enjoy the game.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that you cannot join a Bedrock Edition server off of your&nbsp;Xbox, PS4, Nintendo Switch, or any other similar platform. It can only be joined from PC (Windows 10 Edition), IOS, and Android.</p>



<p>The directions on creating a server are directed to creating one through Any Hosting. You can also create one on your home computer, but this is not recommended as many factors play into owning a server such as DDoS protection, 24/7 uptime, support, etc. All of which are provided by Any Hosting Comapny.</p>



<p>How to create a Minecraft Server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the&nbsp;pricing page&nbsp;on our website. You are going to see a few different plans here. We have a guide that goes over how much ram you will need&nbsp;here.</li><li>Once you decide what plan you want, go ahead and click on “Order Now”, then proceed to follow the instructions.</li><li>Once you have paid for your server, you will receive an email with all of your account information for our Game Panel. With Hosting, the server is created for you.</li><li>On the Game Panel, you will see your IP address. This can be used to connect to the server.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Minecraft Java Edition Server</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft and go into the “Multiplayer” tab.</li><li>Towards the bottom, click on “Add Server”. Put any name under “Server Name” and then enter the server IP address and port, then press “Done”.</li><li>After pressing done, this will take you back to the multiplayer tab, you should see the server now listed. Select the server and press “Join Server”. You should now be connected to the server.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Minecraft Bedrock Edition Server</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft and press “Play”.</li><li>Select the “Servers” tab, then press “Add Server”.</li><li>Fill in any name for “Server Name”, then type in the IP address without the port into the “Server Address” slot. After that, fill in the “Port” slot with your server port.</li><li>Press “Save”, then scroll down and click on the server to join it.</li></ol>



<h3>Realms</h3>



<p>Alternatively, if you do not want to use server hosting, you can use Minecraft’s built-in Realm’s. This is not recommended as Realm’s does not allow the use of mods/plugins, it limits player slots significantly and restricts who can and cannot join, and it’s quite pricey for what you are getting. Ontop of all of that, you do not get any of the benefits that come along with server hosting such as 24/7 support, one-click&nbsp;modpack&nbsp;and gametype installations, the ability to create a public world that anyone can join, and much more. However, if you want to play Minecraft with friends on Xbox, PS4 or Switch.</p>



<p>How to create a Realms Server for Java Edition</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft and press “Minecraft Realms”</li><li>To the bottom of Minecraft, click on “Buy Realm”. This will take you to Minecraft’s website where you can set up your subscription.</li><li>If you already had a Realm setup, you will see a listing with it. You can press “Subscribe” which will also take you to Minecraft’s website so you can set up the Realms.</li><li>Once you have paid for it, head back to the Realms tab in Minecraft and you should see the listing with a green light. Press it and then click the “Play” button.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Realms Server in Java Edition</p>



<ol><li>To join a Realms Server, you must have been invited.</li><li>To invite someone to your Realms, go to Configure Realms, then press the Players tab.</li><li>Click on the + and type in your friend’s username to send them an invitation.</li><li>To the top of your Realms page, you should see a little icon named “New Invitations!”. If you click that, you can see the Realms you have been invited to. Simply select it and press “Play”.</li></ol>



<p>How to create a Realms Server for Bedrock Edition</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft, and click “Play”.</li><li>On this page, you will need to be in the “Worlds” tabs.</li><li>If you are signed in to an Xbox Live account, you can start a new Realms by clicking on “Create New”. Once you click that, you can either create a new world or use a premade Realms world.</li><li>If you aren’t signed in, you can use the free 30-day trial option. Locate the section named “Realms” at the top and click on the listing for your Realm.</li><li>Click on “Buy Now” and follow the instructions to pay for your first month.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Realms Server in Bedrock Edition</p>



<ol><li>You need to be invited to a Realms in order to join it.</li><li>You can invite a player by clicking on the pencil icon next to your Realm’s name, then select “Members”.</li><li>Click the “Share” tab which will bring up an invite link. Send this link to your friends. This will prompt them to sign in/sign up to their Xbox Live account, then it will add them to your Realm’s&nbsp;whitelist.</li><li>If you are invited to your friend’s Realm, click on the “Friends” tab and you should see a listing, select it to join.</li></ol>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>It’s time to jump into the world of Minecraft along with your friends! With so many different ways to join, you may have trouble deciding which is the best option for you. If you want to just play Vanilla Minecraft with people who live in the same house as you, the LAN option is the best. If you want to play Vanilla Minecraft with a few friends across the world, either Realms or a server is best. Having the server&nbsp;would be more cost-effective&nbsp;than realms as they are generally going to be cheaper than the Realm’s starting price at $3.99 for just 2 players. Minecraft Servers also allow for customizations such as plugins and mods, and for expansion globally so your server can attract more than just your group of friends. If you host your server with Hosting Company, you also get access to our premade gametypes, modpacks, 24/7 support, and customized game panel. All of this information may seem like quite a bit, but once you get the hang of it, it’s not too bad. Playing Minecraft with friends adds a whole new experience to the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Minecraft ‘Failed to Verify Username’ Error FIX</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[account migration minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to migrate your minecraft account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[migrate minecraft account without email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[migrate minecraft to microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17 news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft acccount migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft account migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft cape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft capes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft free cape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java account migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft migrate account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft update]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=43</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview You may have tried to join your&#160;Minecraft server&#160;and been rejected due to the error “Failed to verify username” or “Invalid Session”. This issue is normally because the client’s launcher failed to authenticate with Mojang’s session servers. Luckily, you can fix this error with just a few steps. You may also be running a non-premium ... <a title="Minecraft ‘Failed to Verify Username’ Error FIX" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/" aria-label="More on Minecraft ‘Failed to Verify Username’ Error FIX">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/2741284536420253035#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yYeFHnfPlL8/X_nE6pEMuNI/AAAAAAAAADI/yjNFOq4Y-rIJv6d0sxTjX5mDVptsTbCmwCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25285%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>You may have tried to join your&nbsp;Minecraft server&nbsp;and been rejected due to the error “Failed to verify username” or “Invalid Session”. This issue is normally because the client’s launcher failed to authenticate with Mojang’s session servers. Luckily, you can fix this error with just a few steps.</p>



<p>You may also be running a non-premium version of Minecraft. If you did not pay for Minecraft, you will not be allowed to join most servers due to the server running in online mode, however, it can be changed to offline mode fairly easily.</p>



<h2>How to resolve</h2>



<p>How to resolve on a premium server</p>



<ol><li>Close your game.</li><li>Log off your account from your launcher.</li><li>You will then be asked to type in your email and password again, please do.</li><li>Once logged in, you can then start your game and join the server.</li></ol>



<p>How to allow cracked players on your server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the Game Panel and stop the server.</li><li>To the left of the panel click “Config Files” and then click “Server Settings”.</li><li>Locate “Online Mode” and set it to disabled, then click save.</li><li>Head back to the Game Panel dashboard and turn the server back on. It should now let you join.</li></ol>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>After restarting the launcher, players still can’t join<br>If you are using premium Minecraft and have already followed the steps on to resolve the error and still cannot join, try restarting the server.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to OP Yourself In Minecraft Server</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prison server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prison server ip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prisons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op skyblock server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op skyblock server 1.8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison break]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison cell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison ep 1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison escape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prisons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft skyblock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft skyblock server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft uhc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[op kits minecraft opprison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[op prison server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prison minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[server]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview When you create your&#160;server, you probably expect to have every permission/command. You may want to give other players access to every command as well. For Minecraft servers, this is done simply by making yourself Op. Being Op basically gives you every permission the server has to offer. This is what allows you to use ... <a title="How to OP Yourself In Minecraft Server" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/" aria-label="More on How to OP Yourself In Minecraft Server">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/4425611516391732216#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tzXzWio4sbE/X_nEj5fOiKI/AAAAAAAAADA/gPYACxDRGvojzuE_l302SX5KArrrtdIBgCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25284%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>When you create your&nbsp;server, you probably expect to have every permission/command. You may want to give other players access to every command as well. For Minecraft servers, this is done simply by making yourself Op. Being Op basically gives you every permission the server has to offer. This is what allows you to use commands such as /gamemode. &nbsp;The owner of the server is automatically set however you may want to set other players as operators. We will be walking you through the different levels of OP, how to set a server operator and how to remove an operator.<br>In the&nbsp;1.7.10 update, Op Permission Levels were added. These allow you to control how much control on the server the operators will have. If you want to add individual permissions for certain players/groups, you will need a plugin such as PermissionsEx.</p>



<h2>How to set and remove OP</h2>



<p>How to set someone to OP on your Minecraft server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the game panel and to the left click on the console tab.</li><li>In the command line type “op ” and press enter.</li><li>You should see a message that says “Player is now an operator”.</li><li>You can also do this in-game by typing “/op ”. You must be opped in order to use this command.</li></ol>



<p>How to unop someone on your Minecraft server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the game panel and to the left click on the console tab.</li><li>In the command line type “deop ” and press enter.</li><li>You should see a message that says “Player is no longer an operator”.</li><li>You can also do this in-game by typing “/deop ”. You will need to be opped in order to use this command.</li></ol>



<h2>OP levels</h2>



<p>Levels<br>Each OP level inherits the levels before it. So for example, level 3 also has the commands and abilities of level 2 and level 1. The Op Permission Levels were released during the 1.7.10<br>development, so this will not apply to any version under 1.7.10.</p>



<ul><li>Level 1 – This will allow server operators to bypass the default spawn protection. This is the lowest level of OP and does not have any commands included.</li><li>Level 2 – If you have level 2 set, operators will be able to use the following commands: /gamerule, /give, /effect, /clear, /difficulty, /summon, /tp, /gamemode, and /setblock. They will also have permission to edit&nbsp;command blocks.</li><li>Level 3 – This level will allow server operators to use the following commands: /ban, /kick, /deop, and /op.</li><li>Level 4 – This is the highest level of OP, it allows server operators to use the /stop command.</li></ul>



<p>How to set the OP level</p>



<ol><li>Head to the game panel and stop the server.</li><li>To the left of the panel, click on “Config Files”.</li><li>Click “Server Settings” and locate “Op Permission Level”.</li><li>On the dropdown, you will see all of the levels you can set. Choose which level you want the server operators to have and press Save.</li><li>Start the server.</li></ol>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>Not having access to all of the commands even when you are opped<br>If you have Opped yourself but still do not have permissions like /gamemode, it is likely that you have the wrong OP level set. You can edit this by stopping the server, going to config files, “Server Settings”, locating/changing “Op Permission Level” to your desired level, saving, then starting the server back up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Add Resource Packs To Minecraft Server</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-resource-packs-to-minecraft-server/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-resource-packs-to-minecraft-server/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft resource pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft resource packs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft texture pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best resource packs for minecraft 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best texture packs for minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft resource pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft resource packs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft resource packs 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft texture pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft texture packs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft vanilla resource pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resource pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resource pack 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resource packs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texture pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top 10 minecraft texture packs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top packs for minecraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview Adding a Resource Pack to your&#160;Minecraft server&#160;is an excellent way to bring excitement to the visual aspects of your community’s gameplay. With thousands of texture packs, there are endless possibilities to create your perfect server. While installing a resource pack to your server can be tricky, we will walk you through the process to ... <a title="How To Add Resource Packs To Minecraft Server" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-resource-packs-to-minecraft-server/" aria-label="More on How To Add Resource Packs To Minecraft Server">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/750870351060855106#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vfYnG6-Nu3k/X_nDJIjqVDI/AAAAAAAAAC0/77QmgAN_HEwAPev42vi137mqLtNm8svlgCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25283%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>Adding a Resource Pack to your&nbsp;Minecraft server&nbsp;is an excellent way to bring excitement to the visual aspects of your community’s gameplay. With thousands of texture packs, there are endless possibilities to create your perfect server. While installing a resource pack to your server can be tricky, we will walk you through the process to ensure a smooth installation.</p>



<h2>How to Install</h2>



<p>Finding a pack:</p>



<ol><li>The pack needs to come from an official website such as CurseForge (<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/750870351060855106#">https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs</a>).</li><li>Confirm that the resource pack is made for the version of Minecraft your server is running.</li><li>Download the pack to a known directory on your computer.</li></ol>



<h2>Setting Up Dropbox</h2>



<ol><li>Sign into the Dropbox website.</li><li>To the right of the Dropbox site, click the “Upload Files” button.</li><li>Navigate to your chosen resource pack on your computer, select it, and click “Open”.</li><li>Wait for the file to upload.</li><li>When it has finished click done.</li><li>Find your texture pack in the Dropbox file list and press the share button.</li><li>Ensure that your link settings for the file are set to “Anyone with the link can see it.”</li><li>Copy the link to your clipboard.</li></ol>



<h2>Configuring Your Server</h2>



<ol><li><ol><li>Login to your Multicraft panel, select and stop your Minecraft server.</li><li>Click on “Files” and then “Config Files“</li><li>Click server settings.</li><li>In the “resource-pack=” field, paste the public link you copied from Dropbox.</li><li>The public link you copied from Dropbox must be changed from https://www.dropbox.com/somestring…?dl=0 to https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/somestring…?dl=1 You have to change the 0 at the end to 1.</li><li>Click save at the bottom of the page</li><li>Start your server again.</li></ol>&nbsp;Common IssuesFPS is dropping after you install the packIf a player is getting this issue, the resource pack may be too intense for their computer to handle. Using a less demanding pack for the server will allow players to use the pack with less worry for lag.Players clicking Yes on the resource pack popup but nothing changes.If when the player clicks “Yes” on the popup and nothing happens, this is generally due to an issue with the link inputted in the server settings. First, make sure that the Dropbox was set to “Anyone with the link can see it.” and that the link was changed from https://www.dropbox.com/somestring…?dl=0 to https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/somestring…?dl=1. This can also be from the texture pack not being made for the server version you are running.</li></ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-resource-packs-to-minecraft-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Install Minecraft Data Packs</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-minecraft-data-packs/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-minecraft-data-packs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#datapack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1 command in minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datapack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datapacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to install datapack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 datapack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft command]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft command block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft data pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft data packs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft datapack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft datapacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft datapacks 1.15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft datapacks 1.15.2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft datapacks 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one command in minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top 10 minecraft data packs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview There are many great ways to further customize your Minecraft gameplay. One of the easiest ways to customize your server is with the use of datapacks. You can use datapacks to add new advancements, functions, loot tables, structures, and more. This is a great alternative to adding mods/plugins onto your server as it does ... <a title="How To Install Minecraft Data Packs" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-minecraft-data-packs/" aria-label="More on How To Install Minecraft Data Packs">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/4088392038441191749#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Q9kaKqceRvk/X_nCNaijPcI/AAAAAAAAACo/D5YTJvQa0CEVxYSfqLw3jcuMn21sKOAoACLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25282%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>There are many great ways to further customize your Minecraft gameplay. One of the easiest ways to customize your server is with the use of datapacks. You can use datapacks to add new advancements, functions, loot tables, structures, and more. This is a great alternative to adding mods/plugins onto your server as it does not require installation client-side or for you to&nbsp;change your server version&nbsp;from Vanilla Minecraft. Keep in mind that they are only made for&nbsp;Java Edition&nbsp;and not&nbsp;Bedrock Edition. Datapacks can be added to your&nbsp;Minecraft server&nbsp;easily and we will walk you through each step of the process.</p>



<h2>How to add datapacks</h2>



<p>Finding a pack</p>



<ol><li>The pack needs to come from an trusted site such as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/4088392038441191749#">Vanilla Tweaks</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/4088392038441191749#">Gamemode 4</a>.</li><li>Confirm that the datapack you want to download is made for the version of Minecraft that your server is running.</li><li>Download the pack to a known directory on your computer. It generally downloads as a .zip, do not extract this.</li></ol>



<p>Uploading the datapack to the server</p>



<ol><li>Stop your server</li><li>Access your server files through an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/4088392038441191749#">FTP</a>&nbsp;client such as FileZilla.</li><li>Open the world folder and then enter the datapacks directory.</li><li>Make sure that you are opening the world folder that your server is set to load. You can check the name of world your server is loading in the world field on the main page of the game panel.</li><li>Drag the datapack you downloaded previously into the datapacks folder.</li><li>Once the file is fully uploaded, head back to the game panel and start the server.</li></ol>



<p>Commands<br>The datapack command was added after 1.13, so these are not relevant for any versions under 1.13.</p>



<ul><li>/datapack disable: Disables a datapack of choosing</li><li>/datapack enable: Enables a datapack of choosing</li><li>/datapack list: List all of the enabled/disabled datapacks</li></ul>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>Datapack doesn’t show in the server<br>The datapack not showing is generally from the file not being uploaded to the correct directory. Enter your world folder, than datapacks folder to ensure that the datapack is properly uploaded. Also, make sure that you did not unzip the pack. If you check both of these and still are experiencing issues, make sure that the datapack is made for the same version of Minecraft that your server is running.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-minecraft-data-packs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Install the Dynmap Plugin for Minecraft</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-the-dynmap-plugin-for-minecraft/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-the-dynmap-plugin-for-minecraft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bukkit dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap bukkit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap bukkit plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap minecraft plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap plugin 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap plugin tutorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dynmap tutorial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google maps plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to install dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup a dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup dynmap plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to use dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bukkit plugin dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dynmap plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin tutorial dynmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=31</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview One of the great ways to customize your&#160;Minecraft server&#160;is with plugins. With thousands of plugins, your server has endless possibilities from creating Factions to having an online map of your server. Dynmap is an awesome way to expand your server outside of the normal Minecraft gameplay. With this plugin, you can create an online ... <a title="How to Install the Dynmap Plugin for Minecraft" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-the-dynmap-plugin-for-minecraft/" aria-label="More on How to Install the Dynmap Plugin for Minecraft">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/2752919920969240836#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Tt9V_DwRw60/X_nAzY_pJgI/AAAAAAAAACY/j_duqO4O-SMe6fknTaDzmI-qBiOmnGyfACLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/novaskin-minecraft-wallpaper%2B%25286%2529.jpeg" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>One of the great ways to customize your&nbsp;Minecraft server&nbsp;is with plugins. With thousands of plugins, your server has endless possibilities from creating Factions to having an online map of your server. Dynmap is an awesome way to expand your server outside of the normal Minecraft gameplay. With this plugin, you can create an online webpage that essentially works like a google map for your Minecraft worlds. Many plugins can also be implemented into the Dynmap map such as&nbsp;Factions&nbsp;and Towny. If you are looking for a way to enhance your server further, Dynmap is the way to go. The setup process is decently easily and we will walk you through each step of it.</p>



<h2>How to install Dynmap</h2>



<p>Install through the panel</p>



<ol><li>Make sure your server is running Bukkit, Spigot, or Paper. You can check this in the jar dropdown on the game panel dashboard.</li><li>To the left of the game panel, press the Plugins List tab.</li><li>Type in “Dynmap” in the name search and scroll until you find it. Then click on it to open the download page.</li><li>At the bottom of the page, check the version you have selected. It’s good to cross-reference this to the official Bukkit or Spigot page.</li><li>Find the correct version from the version dropdown, select it and press install.</li><li>Go back to the Game Panel and restart your server. You can check if the plugin was installed successfully by typing “pl” into the console.</li></ol>



<p>Install through FTP</p>



<ol><li>Go to the official Dynmap page on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/2752919920969240836#">Bukkit</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/2752919920969240836#">Spigot</a>&nbsp;and click on the File tab.</li><li>Find the update that is compatible with your server version and press the download icon.</li><li>Head to the Game Panel and click FTP File Access to the left of the panel.</li><li>Once you login to the FTP File Access you will see a list of your files. Open the plugins folder and click “Upload” to the top left of the page.</li><li>Drag your plugin over to the right side of the page and wait for it to reach 100%.</li><li>Head back to the Game Panel and restart your server. The plugin should now be installed. You can check this by typing “pl” into the console.</li></ol>



<h2>How to setup Dynmap</h2>



<p>Configuration</p>



<ol><li>Stop your server.</li><li>To the left of the game panel, click FTP File Access, then enter the plugins folder.</li><li>Find the folder named Dynmap and open it, then locate the file named configuration.txt and press edit to the right of it.</li><li>Once in the configuration, locate deftemplatesuffix and set it to vlowres or lowres.</li><li>Scroll down to webserver-port and change it to any four digit port higher than 1024. The default port set is generally taken by someone else so you must use a random one.</li><li>Locate image-format: and set it to jpg.</li><li>Press Save, head back to the game panel and start your server.</li><li>Once the server has fully started, go to your console and type in “dynmap fullrender WORLDNAME”.</li></ol>



<h2>How to add a resource pack</h2>



<p>Finding a pack:</p>



<ol><li>The pack needs to come from an trusted website such as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/2752919920969240836#">CurseForge</a>.</li><li>Confirm that the resource pack is made for the version of Minecraft your server is running.</li><li>Download the pack to a known directory on your computer.</li></ol>



<p>Adding to Dynmap</p>



<ol><li>Stop your server.</li><li>To the left of the game panel, click FTP File Access, then enter the plugins folder.</li><li>Find the folder named Dynmap and open it, then open the texturepacks folder.</li><li>To the left of the page click Upload and drag in the pack you previously downloaded.</li><li>Wait until it is fully uploaded and then go back one directory to the main Dynmap folder.</li><li>Locate the file named shaders.txt and press edit to the right of it.</li><li>You are going to want to clear the current contents of this file and add the following:<br><code></code>shaders: &#8211; class: org.dynmap.hdmap.TexturePackHDShader name: stdtexture texturepack: (Full name of texturepack here)<code></code></li><li>From this, the only part you will be changing is “texturepack:”. In this spot, you will put the full name of the file including the extension. For example, “texturepack: Faithful+1.13.2-rv2.zip”.</li><li>Once you get that set, save the file and head back to the game panel.</li><li>Start your server and you will want to do a full render of the map by typing dynmap fullrender into the console.</li></ol>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Dynmap is a great way to customize your Minecraft server. You can integrate your region plugins such as Towny or Factions to really bring a realistic feel to your community. While Dynmap is great, make sure that you are only using it if your server has enough resources to support it as it can be a bit resource intensive. However, you can upgrade your server at any time!</p>



<p>To upgrade your server, log in to your billing area at the top of the site. In the top menu select services, my services, select the server you want to upgrade, then hit the upgrade/downgrade option. You can select your upgrade there. After you have paid simply restart the server for the upgrade to be applied.</p>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>Port is taken<br>When configuring Dynmap, it’s important that you change the webserver-port to a random 4 digit number. If you run into an error saying the port is taken, you will need to change it to another number.</p>



<p>Hi res causing performance issues<br>It is very important to set the deftemplatesuffix to vlowres or lowres, if you do not to this you will almost always run into performance issues on the server.</p>



<p>Using MySQL and not FileTree<br>Maps can become several gigabytes in size, which can tank your MySQL performance. It is best you use the default setting, FileTree.</p>



<p>Texture pack not loading<br>If you have set the texture pack and it is still not working, there are a few things you need to check for. The first is that you set the “texturepack:” section to the exact filename of the resource pack you uploaded. If that’s correct, check that the resource pack you downloaded is made for the same version of Minecraft that you are running.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-install-the-dynmap-plugin-for-minecraft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Add Mods to a Minecraft Server</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1.16.3 minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazing minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asianhalfsquat mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft mods 1.16.3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best minecraft mods 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best new minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool new minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mod showcase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 1.16.3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods 2020]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods java]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mods pc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new minecraft mods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top 10 minecraft mods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview If you have been playing&#160;Vanilla Minecraft, or using a premade modpack, it is likely that you have already explored all there is to do. Why not start exploring into customizing your server further? A great way to customize your server is by adding mods. Whether you are adding them to an existing&#160;modpack&#160;or to your ... <a title="How to Add Mods to a Minecraft Server" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/" aria-label="More on How to Add Mods to a Minecraft Server">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pmk3nIK96Os/X_m_o2S7ALI/AAAAAAAAACI/zRz5Khv1-aAnjzoVNoO_UKPkR0V94-0SQCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/novaskin-minecraft-wallpaper%2B%25285%2529.jpeg" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>If you have been playing&nbsp;Vanilla Minecraft, or using a premade modpack, it is likely that you have already explored all there is to do. Why not start exploring into customizing your server further? A great way to customize your server is by adding mods. Whether you are adding them to an existing&nbsp;modpack&nbsp;or to your current Forge setup, adding mods is a great way to open up new possibilities. Mods can be added with just a few steps and we will walk you through each of them so you can build your dream&nbsp;server.</p>



<p>When running a modded server, do not forget that you need to have the mods downloaded on your Minecraft client. This also applies if you are adding additional mods to an already created modpack. In order to run mods on your client, you will need to&nbsp;install Forge client side.</p>



<h2>How to Install Mods on a Minecraft Server</h2>



<p>Downloading mods</p>



<ol><li>You need to get the mods from&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#">CurseForge</a>&nbsp;or the mod authors official site. Doing this ensures that you won’t get corrupted files or viruses.</li><li>Once you decide on a mod you want, click the name to open the mod page.</li><li>Open the Files tab to view the versions. To the right of the version you want, press download. It’s best to download the latest recommended update for your version of Minecraft.</li><li>Head back to the mods page and open the Relations tab. This is very important as these are the mods you need for it to work correctly. If you don’t download the dependencies, the server will not function properly, or at all.</li></ol>



<p>Uploading mods</p>



<ol><li>Make sure that your server is set to Forge under the jar dropdown. You can find a tutorial on changing server versions&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#">here</a>. Note that you need to run forge before you put the mods in, to create the mods folder, and if you do not your mods will be deleted.</li><li>Stop the server.</li><li>To the left of the game panel, click on FTP File Access and go into the mods folder.</li><li>Click on “Upload” then simply drag in the mods you have previously downloaded. Wait for the mods to fully upload before leaving this page.</li><li>When you upload mods, it is highly recommended that you generate a new world to ensure that there is no corruption. You can find our guide on making a new world&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/1875636301588821341#">here</a>.</li><li>Once they are uploaded, head back to the Game Panel and start the server. Once the server is fully started, you are safe to connect.</li></ol>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>Incorrect Forge version</p>



<p>The mods you have uploaded to the server may not always be compatible with the Forge version we have available from our jar selector. If this is the case, you will need to install the correct version of Forge for your mod manually. We have a tutorial on uploading a custom version of Forge&nbsp;here.</p>



<p>Server is crashing on startup</p>



<p>The&nbsp;server crashing&nbsp;during the startup process can be common on Forge servers if they are not setup correctly. This can be due to multiple issues. Most commonly this is caused by a duplicate mod, missing dependency mods, or incorrect mod versions.</p>



<p>Server is stuck loading</p>



<p>Many times when modifying the server, the server will need to be confirmed before it will fully start. This happens a lot especially when you remove or add mods. Most of the time in console, you will see&nbsp;Missing Mod Id’s errors. All you need to do to resolve this is type /fml confirm in console.</p>



<p>Duplicate Mods<br>You can detect a duplicate mod from console pretty easily. You will see an error that says “Duplicate Mods” with the mod name listed underneath it. Simply go into the FTP File Access, the mods folder, and delete the extra mod.</p>



<p>Missing Dependency<br>To detect if you have a missing dependency mod, head into the console where you will see an error code that reads something similar to The mod nei (Not Enough Items) requires mod [JEI] to be available From this error, we can see that the&nbsp;missing mod&nbsp;is JEI. You will need to add the mod into the server in order for the server to work again.</p>



<p>Incorrect Mod Version<br>Detecting if the mod is the incorrect version is pretty easy. It will almost always display an error stating that it is for a different version of Forge. It will look similar to File jei_1.12.2-4.15.0.268.jar is for an older version of Forge and cannot be loaded. If you have this issue, make sure that the mod you are using&nbsp;has an update&nbsp;for the version of Forge you are running. If it doesn’t, then you won’t be able to use the mod on your server.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-add-mods-to-a-minecraft-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Minecraft: Dripstone Caves v.1.17 What&#8217;s Coming ?</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-dripstone-caves-v-1-17-whats-coming/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-dripstone-caves-v-1-17-whats-coming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[v.1.17]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone cave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone cave minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone caves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone caves biome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone caves minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dripstone minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17 dripstone caves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17 snapshot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft cave update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft caves & cliffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft caves & cliffs update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft caves and cliffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft caves and cliffs update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dripstone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dripstone cave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dripstone caves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft lush caves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pointed dripstone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Minecraft: Dripstone Caves v.1.17 What&#8217;s Coming ?Overview So, 1.17 is on the horizon while snapshots are coming out the woodwork left and right. And what do they decide to drop on our doorstep? Dripstone. Minecraft introduces something that the modding community has adored for so long in improved cave generation, biomes. With that, comes the ... <a title="Minecraft: Dripstone Caves v.1.17 What&#8217;s Coming ?" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-dripstone-caves-v-1-17-whats-coming/" aria-label="More on Minecraft: Dripstone Caves v.1.17 What&#8217;s Coming ?">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Minecraft: Dripstone Caves v.1.17 What&#8217;s Coming ?<br><img loading="lazy" alt="dripstone caves" height="360" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/10/09213930/dripstone-caves.jpg" width="640"><br>Overview</h2>



<p>So, 1.17 is on the horizon while snapshots are coming out the woodwork left and right. And what do they decide to drop on our doorstep? Dripstone. Minecraft introduces something that the modding community has adored for so long in improved cave generation, biomes. With that, comes the newest and coolest biome in the latest snapshot, 20w49a, the Dripstone Caves.</p>



<p>Today, we’ll be going over the fairly short yet interesting compilation of mechanics surrounding Dripstone. Let’s get started.</p>



<h3>Dripstone</h3>



<p>If you don’t know what Dripstone is, Dripstone is a new block that will be included in the newest 1.17 Caves and Cliffs update. They can generate on the floors and ceilings of the newest biome, Dripstone Caves. They come in two variants. Stalactites and Stalagmites. These are basically fancy ways of saying top or bottom Dripstone. If it descends from the ceiling, it is a Stalactite. If it sprouts from the ground, its is a Stalagmite. That’s all the information we have so far on these things in regards to formation!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/12/11202435/dripstone.png" alt="dripstone"/></figure>



<h3>Dripstone Caves</h3>



<p><br>Dripstone MechanicsDripstone Caves are the main, and first underground biome where Dripstone spawns. The block will cover most of the ceiling and floor, posing quite the hazard to mobs and players alike. They also look extremely majestic when making large formations around a cave.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/12/11202429/dripstone-dripping.jpg" alt="dripstone dripping"/></figure>



<p>Drip Drop&nbsp;– Dripstone actually drips! Putting a source block of lava or water on top of a Stalactite will eventually lead to that liquid dripping off the tip. Leaving a Cauldron under will actually fill it over time. This also means you can now fill Cauldrons with Lava!</p>



<p>INFINITE LAVA&nbsp;– With the new mechanic that I have dubbed ‘Drip Drop’ you can now infinitely produce lava! All you need is one bucket full of lava, and have the Dripstone drop it in a Cauldron. Do this multiple times to constantly produce more lava!</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Dripstone is a fairly developed addition to Minecraft which I think is a net gain for 1.17. It adds in Stalactites and Stalagmites like the modded community has begged for while also keeping that beautiful Minecraft aesthetic. On top of that, it adds some mechanical functionality which is always appreciated. Also, an awesome themed underground biome to boot! Overall, a great welcome addition to the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-dripstone-caves-v-1-17-whats-coming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
