<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>minecraft server &#8211; MineVote &#8211; Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/tag/minecraft-server/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog</link>
	<description>Minecraft Server Guide</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:39:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Play Minecraft with Friends ?</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beating minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beating minecraft but my friend tries to stop me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft hunter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft manhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft speedrun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream minecraft youtube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream smp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream speedrun minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but lava rises every minute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but water rises every minute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft dream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft manhunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft survival]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=47</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview For years,&#160;Minecraft&#160;has been known as one of the world’s most popular video games. While many may think that this is due to the expansive features and seemingly endless possibilities in single-player, one of the main reasons is the ability to play Minecraft with your friends – even those who are far away. Minecraft singleplayer ... <a title="How to Play Minecraft with Friends ?" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/" aria-label="More on How to Play Minecraft with Friends ?">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/7556756269990714606#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dzFwHTU702s/X_qEH3X9RiI/AAAAAAAAADg/pYERSAVHTSg1lIt78REhmaOrQx8g-w_twCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25286%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>For years,&nbsp;Minecraft&nbsp;has been known as one of the world’s most popular video games. While many may think that this is due to the expansive features and seemingly endless possibilities in single-player, one of the main reasons is the ability to play Minecraft with your friends – even those who are far away.</p>



<p>Minecraft singleplayer is great for sure, however, one can really expand their gameplay experience simply by playing multiplayer with others. There are many ways to play with friends, including LAN servers which allow you to connect with players who are on the same internet as you, Realms which allow you to play across the globe, and servers which is by far the most popular option as it allows you to play modded Minecraft with your friends. You may be wondering how you can play Minecraft online and which option is best for you. That is why in this guide we’ll be breaking down the different ways to connect and play together.</p>



<h2>How to Play Minecraft with Friends on PC</h2>



<h3>LAN World</h3>



<p>In Minecraft, you have the ability to connect with friends through LAN. This will be accessible only to others within your local network. For example, if your friend is over at your house and connected to your wifi, you can create a LAN world to join.</p>



<p>How to make a LAN world</p>



<ol><li>Open up Minecraft, and join your single-player world.</li><li>Press the escape key to open up your Game Menu.</li><li>Press “Open to LAN”, then select if you want to allow cheats and what game mode you want the other users to have, then press “Start LAN World”.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a LAN world</p>



<ol><li>In Minecraft, click on the “Multiplayer” tab.</li><li>Scroll to the bottom of the list, you should see a message that says “Scanning for games on your local network”.</li><li>Once it finds the world, you will see a listing named “LAN World” with your friends username and the world name under it.</li><li>Double click it to join, or select it and press “Join Server”.</li></ol>



<h3>Minecraft Server</h3>



<p>Owning a Minecraft server is one of the best ways for you and your friends to connect with each other through Minecraft. Having your own server stands on top of the other options for a few reasons: You can set it to any version of Minecraft, you can modify it past Vanilla, and servers don’t cap the number of players who can join (of course, you would need a powerful server depending on the number of players you want online.) Playing Minecraft Java Edition with friends on a modded server is one of the most flexible, and fun, ways to enjoy the game.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that you cannot join a Bedrock Edition server off of your&nbsp;Xbox, PS4, Nintendo Switch, or any other similar platform. It can only be joined from PC (Windows 10 Edition), IOS, and Android.</p>



<p>The directions on creating a server are directed to creating one through Any Hosting. You can also create one on your home computer, but this is not recommended as many factors play into owning a server such as DDoS protection, 24/7 uptime, support, etc. All of which are provided by Any Hosting Comapny.</p>



<p>How to create a Minecraft Server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the&nbsp;pricing page&nbsp;on our website. You are going to see a few different plans here. We have a guide that goes over how much ram you will need&nbsp;here.</li><li>Once you decide what plan you want, go ahead and click on “Order Now”, then proceed to follow the instructions.</li><li>Once you have paid for your server, you will receive an email with all of your account information for our Game Panel. With Hosting, the server is created for you.</li><li>On the Game Panel, you will see your IP address. This can be used to connect to the server.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Minecraft Java Edition Server</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft and go into the “Multiplayer” tab.</li><li>Towards the bottom, click on “Add Server”. Put any name under “Server Name” and then enter the server IP address and port, then press “Done”.</li><li>After pressing done, this will take you back to the multiplayer tab, you should see the server now listed. Select the server and press “Join Server”. You should now be connected to the server.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Minecraft Bedrock Edition Server</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft and press “Play”.</li><li>Select the “Servers” tab, then press “Add Server”.</li><li>Fill in any name for “Server Name”, then type in the IP address without the port into the “Server Address” slot. After that, fill in the “Port” slot with your server port.</li><li>Press “Save”, then scroll down and click on the server to join it.</li></ol>



<h3>Realms</h3>



<p>Alternatively, if you do not want to use server hosting, you can use Minecraft’s built-in Realm’s. This is not recommended as Realm’s does not allow the use of mods/plugins, it limits player slots significantly and restricts who can and cannot join, and it’s quite pricey for what you are getting. Ontop of all of that, you do not get any of the benefits that come along with server hosting such as 24/7 support, one-click&nbsp;modpack&nbsp;and gametype installations, the ability to create a public world that anyone can join, and much more. However, if you want to play Minecraft with friends on Xbox, PS4 or Switch.</p>



<p>How to create a Realms Server for Java Edition</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft and press “Minecraft Realms”</li><li>To the bottom of Minecraft, click on “Buy Realm”. This will take you to Minecraft’s website where you can set up your subscription.</li><li>If you already had a Realm setup, you will see a listing with it. You can press “Subscribe” which will also take you to Minecraft’s website so you can set up the Realms.</li><li>Once you have paid for it, head back to the Realms tab in Minecraft and you should see the listing with a green light. Press it and then click the “Play” button.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Realms Server in Java Edition</p>



<ol><li>To join a Realms Server, you must have been invited.</li><li>To invite someone to your Realms, go to Configure Realms, then press the Players tab.</li><li>Click on the + and type in your friend’s username to send them an invitation.</li><li>To the top of your Realms page, you should see a little icon named “New Invitations!”. If you click that, you can see the Realms you have been invited to. Simply select it and press “Play”.</li></ol>



<p>How to create a Realms Server for Bedrock Edition</p>



<ol><li>Open Minecraft, and click “Play”.</li><li>On this page, you will need to be in the “Worlds” tabs.</li><li>If you are signed in to an Xbox Live account, you can start a new Realms by clicking on “Create New”. Once you click that, you can either create a new world or use a premade Realms world.</li><li>If you aren’t signed in, you can use the free 30-day trial option. Locate the section named “Realms” at the top and click on the listing for your Realm.</li><li>Click on “Buy Now” and follow the instructions to pay for your first month.</li></ol>



<p>How to join a Realms Server in Bedrock Edition</p>



<ol><li>You need to be invited to a Realms in order to join it.</li><li>You can invite a player by clicking on the pencil icon next to your Realm’s name, then select “Members”.</li><li>Click the “Share” tab which will bring up an invite link. Send this link to your friends. This will prompt them to sign in/sign up to their Xbox Live account, then it will add them to your Realm’s&nbsp;whitelist.</li><li>If you are invited to your friend’s Realm, click on the “Friends” tab and you should see a listing, select it to join.</li></ol>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>It’s time to jump into the world of Minecraft along with your friends! With so many different ways to join, you may have trouble deciding which is the best option for you. If you want to just play Vanilla Minecraft with people who live in the same house as you, the LAN option is the best. If you want to play Vanilla Minecraft with a few friends across the world, either Realms or a server is best. Having the server&nbsp;would be more cost-effective&nbsp;than realms as they are generally going to be cheaper than the Realm’s starting price at $3.99 for just 2 players. Minecraft Servers also allow for customizations such as plugins and mods, and for expansion globally so your server can attract more than just your group of friends. If you host your server with Hosting Company, you also get access to our premade gametypes, modpacks, 24/7 support, and customized game panel. All of this information may seem like quite a bit, but once you get the hang of it, it’s not too bad. Playing Minecraft with friends adds a whole new experience to the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-play-minecraft-with-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to OP Yourself In Minecraft Server</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prison server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prison server ip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op prisons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op skyblock server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft op skyblock server 1.8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison break]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison cell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison ep 1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison escape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prison server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft prisons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft skyblock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft skyblock server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft uhc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[op kits minecraft opprison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[op prison server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prison minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[server]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview When you create your&#160;server, you probably expect to have every permission/command. You may want to give other players access to every command as well. For Minecraft servers, this is done simply by making yourself Op. Being Op basically gives you every permission the server has to offer. This is what allows you to use ... <a title="How to OP Yourself In Minecraft Server" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/" aria-label="More on How to OP Yourself In Minecraft Server">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/4425611516391732216#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tzXzWio4sbE/X_nEj5fOiKI/AAAAAAAAADA/gPYACxDRGvojzuE_l302SX5KArrrtdIBgCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25284%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>When you create your&nbsp;server, you probably expect to have every permission/command. You may want to give other players access to every command as well. For Minecraft servers, this is done simply by making yourself Op. Being Op basically gives you every permission the server has to offer. This is what allows you to use commands such as /gamemode. &nbsp;The owner of the server is automatically set however you may want to set other players as operators. We will be walking you through the different levels of OP, how to set a server operator and how to remove an operator.<br>In the&nbsp;1.7.10 update, Op Permission Levels were added. These allow you to control how much control on the server the operators will have. If you want to add individual permissions for certain players/groups, you will need a plugin such as PermissionsEx.</p>



<h2>How to set and remove OP</h2>



<p>How to set someone to OP on your Minecraft server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the game panel and to the left click on the console tab.</li><li>In the command line type “op ” and press enter.</li><li>You should see a message that says “Player is now an operator”.</li><li>You can also do this in-game by typing “/op ”. You must be opped in order to use this command.</li></ol>



<p>How to unop someone on your Minecraft server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the game panel and to the left click on the console tab.</li><li>In the command line type “deop ” and press enter.</li><li>You should see a message that says “Player is no longer an operator”.</li><li>You can also do this in-game by typing “/deop ”. You will need to be opped in order to use this command.</li></ol>



<h2>OP levels</h2>



<p>Levels<br>Each OP level inherits the levels before it. So for example, level 3 also has the commands and abilities of level 2 and level 1. The Op Permission Levels were released during the 1.7.10<br>development, so this will not apply to any version under 1.7.10.</p>



<ul><li>Level 1 – This will allow server operators to bypass the default spawn protection. This is the lowest level of OP and does not have any commands included.</li><li>Level 2 – If you have level 2 set, operators will be able to use the following commands: /gamerule, /give, /effect, /clear, /difficulty, /summon, /tp, /gamemode, and /setblock. They will also have permission to edit&nbsp;command blocks.</li><li>Level 3 – This level will allow server operators to use the following commands: /ban, /kick, /deop, and /op.</li><li>Level 4 – This is the highest level of OP, it allows server operators to use the /stop command.</li></ul>



<p>How to set the OP level</p>



<ol><li>Head to the game panel and stop the server.</li><li>To the left of the panel, click on “Config Files”.</li><li>Click “Server Settings” and locate “Op Permission Level”.</li><li>On the dropdown, you will see all of the levels you can set. Choose which level you want the server operators to have and press Save.</li><li>Start the server.</li></ol>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>Not having access to all of the commands even when you are opped<br>If you have Opped yourself but still do not have permissions like /gamemode, it is likely that you have the wrong OP level set. You can edit this by stopping the server, going to config files, “Server Settings”, locating/changing “Op Permission Level” to your desired level, saving, then starting the server back up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-op-yourself-in-minecraft-server/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[$50 minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[budget minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[custom minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to build a minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to make a minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup a minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to setup a minecraft server 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft but]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft funny moments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft school server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft server 1.16.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft servers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft skeppy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft survival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft troll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft trolling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft youtuber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[server]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports Overview Many times when modifying a server you may experience issues with the&#160;server crashing. These crashes are generally caused by either mods, the world, or the server jar. When a server crashes, it generates a crash report in the FTP File Access. These crash reports break down why the ... <a title="How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/" aria-label="More on How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>&nbsp;How to Read Minecraft Crash Reports</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/7383508844279984698#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CpQiDHwbPrc/X-8DXDpMRkI/AAAAAAAAABk/elJ_fAe3ggcvFL45DjBKCRS3-4gnz5nrACLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/minecraft-1106261_1280.webp" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p><strong><br></strong></p>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>Many times when modifying a server you may experience issues with the&nbsp;server crashing. These crashes are generally caused by either mods, the world, or the server jar. When a server crashes, it generates a crash report in the FTP File Access. These crash reports break down why the server crashes and can help you get a better understanding of what’s wrong and how to fix it. At first look, it may seem confusing but all crash reports are similar and once you know what to look for you will be able to accurately read Minecraft crash reports.</p>



<h2>Understanding a Crash Report</h2>



<p>Where to find the crash reports</p>



<ol><li>Head to your Game Panel and to the left, press FTP File Access and log in.</li><li>Once in FTP File Access, you will see a folder named `crash-reports`. Go ahead and click that. Looking inside of that directory you will notice a file or multiple files.</li><li>Every file is written with the date (2019-08-17) which makes it easy to know when each report was made. When there are several files it’s always best to look at the latest and most recent crash to identify the issue.</li><li>To read the crash report, click the “edit” link to the right of the file.</li></ol>



<p>Reading the Crash Report</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">---- Minecraft Crash Report ----
// Everything's going to plan. No, really, that was supposed to happen.

Time: 1/24/20 7:25 AM
Description: Exception in server tick loop

Missing Mods:
	unknown : need [1.5.2,): have missing

net.minecraftforge.fml.common.MissingModsException: Mod thaumcraft (Thaumcraft) requires [baubles@[1.5.2,)]
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.common.Loader.sortModList(Loader.java:266)
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.common.Loader.loadMods(Loader.java:572)
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.server.FMLServerHandler.beginServerLoading(FMLServerHandler.java:98)
	at net.minecraftforge.fml.common.FMLCommonHandler.onServerStart(FMLCommonHandler.java:333)
	at net.minecraft.server.dedicated.DedicatedServer.func_71197_b(DedicatedServer.java:125)
	at net.minecraft.server.MinecraftServer.run(MinecraftServer.java:486)
	at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:748)
</pre>



<p>This is the top portion of the report where it will have the date, time and stack trace. The stack trace is a report of when a program runs at a certain time in its execution. This will be primarily where we will discover the error that is causing the server or client to crash.<br>It looks like a lot but by looking carefully we can deduce the error by picking certain parts of the stack trace out. In this example, we can tell that a mod is missing due to part of the stack trace saying&nbsp;&#8220;Missing Mods: unknown : need [1.5.2,): have missing&#8221;.&nbsp;If we go down to the next line we can see that it tells&nbsp;&#8220;net.minecraftforge.fml.common.MissingModsException: Mod thaumcraft (Thaumcraft) requires [baubles@[1.5.2,)]&#8221;&nbsp;which translates to the mod Thaumcraft needs the mod Baubles version 1.5.2 in order to run properly.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">A detailed walkthrough of the error, its code path and all known details is as follows:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

-- System Details --
Details:
	Minecraft Version: 1.12.2
	Operating System: Linux (amd64) version 3.10.0-957.27.2.el7.x86_64
	Java Version: 1.8.0_222, Oracle Corporation
	Java VM Version: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (mixed mode), Oracle Corporation
	Memory: 1474787976 bytes (1406 MB) / 2075918336 bytes (1979 MB) up to 2075918336 bytes (1979 MB)
	JVM Flags: 4 total; -Xmx2048M -Xms2048M -XX:+UseConcMarkSweepGC -XX:+CMSClassUnloadingEnabled
	IntCache: cache: 0, tcache: 0, allocated: 0, tallocated: 0
	FML: MCP 9.42 Powered by Forge 14.23.5.2847 5 mods loaded, 5 mods active
	States: 'U' = Unloaded 'L' = Loaded 'C' = Constructed 'H' = Pre-initialized 'I' = Initialized 'J' = Post-initialized 'A' = Available 'D' = Disabled 'E' = Errored

	| State | ID         | Version      | Source                           | Signature |
	|:----- |:---------- |:------------ |:-------------------------------- |:--------- |
	| L     | minecraft  | 1.12.2       | minecraft.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | mcp        | 9.42         | minecraft.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | FML        | 8.0.99.99    | forge1122.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | forge      | 14.23.5.2847 | forge1122.jar                    | None      |
	| L     | thaumcraft | 6.1.BETA26   | Thaumcraft-1.12.2-6.1.BETA26.jar | None      |

	Loaded coremods (and transformers): 
	Profiler Position: N/A (disabled)
	Is Modded: Definitely; Server brand changed to 'fml,forge'
	Type: Dedicated Server (map_server.txt)
</pre>



<p>The second half of the crash report will go over your system details and the states of the mods loading in. This can be very important especially with client-side crashing as you can find our what version of Java they are running, how much ram they have allocated and the versions of the mods to be able to assist them. One of the best tools with crash reports is knowing the States in which a mod loads in. These states are as follows:&nbsp;&#8216;U&#8217; = Unloaded &#8216;L&#8217; = Loaded &#8216;C&#8217; = Constructed &#8216;H&#8217; = Pre-initialized &#8216;I&#8217; = Initialized &#8216;J&#8217; = Post-initialized &#8216;A&#8217; = Available &#8216;D&#8217; = Disabled &#8216;E&#8217; = Errored<br>You can see these states to the left of each mod. In this example, they only made it to the loaded state. So if you have a mod that was UCE that would mean the mod Unloaded, Constructed and than Errored which means there was an error with loading that particular mod causing it to crash so you now know what the exact mod causing the issue is and can look into why it&#8217;s occurring.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>There are hundreds of different reasons that your server may crash, it can be from a world issue, server jar, mods, and far more. As long as you can narrow down what the reason is, the solution should come easier. If you can narrow down it’s a world issue, you can Google the error line to see if there are any solutions or you can restore a backup. With so many different solutions to so many different problems, there isn’t a way to break down each individual error you can get.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-read-minecraft-crash-reports/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
