<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tips &#8211; MineVote &#8211; Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/category/tips/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog</link>
	<description>Minecraft Server Guide</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:41:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Netherite in Minecraft: A Guide</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to find netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 nether update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.16 netherite farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft glitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft how to find netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft how to get netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft nether]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft nether update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite armor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite automatic farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft netherite glitch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft survival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netherite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netherite farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netherite minecraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=53</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Netherite Minecraft’s newest update, the&#160;Nether Update&#160;brings forth many additions that revolve around the&#160;Nether. New biomes, mobs, structures, and even a new ore: Netherite! This will be a brief guide on how to obtain and use the ore for your benefit. We’ll go over each thing you can create, and the reasons you would pursue it ... <a title="Netherite in Minecraft: A Guide" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/" aria-label="More on Netherite in Minecraft: A Guide">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/6716079997427016986#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JDJBwtInwFY/X_qGEAvzINI/AAAAAAAAAD0/9qSruyQ6vzIAu5hc-H_zlHoWsf5RAkWtQCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25288%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Netherite</h2>



<p>Minecraft’s newest update, the&nbsp;Nether Update&nbsp;brings forth many additions that revolve around the&nbsp;Nether. New biomes, mobs, structures, and even a new ore: Netherite! This will be a brief guide on how to obtain and use the ore for your benefit. We’ll go over each thing you can create, and the reasons you would pursue it over Diamond.</p>



<h2>How to get Netherite</h2>



<p>You’ll&nbsp;<img alt="Netherite in Nether" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153832/ancient_debris_mc-300x300.jpg">be looking for the ‘Ancient Debris’ block. It spawns only in the Nether, and you’ll need a Diamond Pickaxe. Netherite spawns mostly in the Y-axis of 8-22, but it can spawn less so in 8-119. (Note: Ancient Debris is explosion-proof, so TNT mining is viable!)</p>



<p>Once you mine the block, it’ll drop ‘Netherite Scrap’ which you’ll need four of. After that, you’ll need four gold. Once you’ve gotten those, this is the crafting recipe for a Netherite Ingot:<br><img alt="netherite" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153859/make_netherite_ingot-300x283.png"></p>



<h2>Crafting Netherite Armor and Tools</h2>



<p>To obtain any<img alt="netherite sword" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153900/zs0clhaigpk41-300x282.png">&nbsp;Netherite tool or armor piece, you’ll need a Diamond variant of the item, and one Netherite Ingot. Then, you need to use the Smithing Table. Any item or armor piece will only require one Netherite Ingot to be upgraded into a Netherite item. This will not remove your enchantments.</p>



<p>That’s it. You just place the diamond tool/armor into the first slot, then the Netherite Ingot into the second slot and out comes a Netherite item! Oddly enough, this is currently the Smithing Table’s only use.</p>



<h2>What’s the point?</h2>



<p>You might have thought to yourself “I already have full Diamond Prot IV, why would I need that minuscule upgrade. To that, I would say you really don’t. This is a very difficult ore to obtain and it’s meant for those players that want true endgame gear.<br>With that being said, Netherite Tools and Armor have some benefits. Here’s the list:<br>-Slightly faster mining speed<br>-Increased durability<br>-Weapons do more damage<br>-Higher enchantment value (determines the quality of enchantments)<br>-They float in lava (pretty nifty!)<br>-Higher knockback prevention than Diamond Armor</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>For the&nbsp;<img alt="netherite meme" src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/07/09153902/EWHDedFXkAANc5L-300x298.jpg">majority of you all, this new armor won’t mean much. In fact, it isn’t even that special. But for the minority out there that love to seek out every special discovery, for the crowd that loves to explore and obtain all that there is to obtain this will be a great addition to Minecraft. Although this will not severely shift the meta of the game, it will make it more interesting for a time. It also looks cool, and that’s always a huge plus! With that said, I’ll see you all next time!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/netherite-in-minecraft-a-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Minecraft ‘Failed to Verify Username’ Error FIX</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[account migration minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to migrate your minecraft account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[migrate minecraft account without email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[migrate minecraft to microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft 1.17 news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft acccount migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft account migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft cape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft capes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft free cape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java account migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft java edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft migrate account]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft migration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft update]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=43</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overview You may have tried to join your&#160;Minecraft server&#160;and been rejected due to the error “Failed to verify username” or “Invalid Session”. This issue is normally because the client’s launcher failed to authenticate with Mojang’s session servers. Luckily, you can fix this error with just a few steps. You may also be running a non-premium ... <a title="Minecraft ‘Failed to Verify Username’ Error FIX" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/" aria-label="More on Minecraft ‘Failed to Verify Username’ Error FIX">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://www.blogger.com/u/5/blog/post/edit/7469356289688488708/2741284536420253035#"><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yYeFHnfPlL8/X_nE6pEMuNI/AAAAAAAAADI/yjNFOq4Y-rIJv6d0sxTjX5mDVptsTbCmwCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h360/download%2B%25285%2529.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>You may have tried to join your&nbsp;Minecraft server&nbsp;and been rejected due to the error “Failed to verify username” or “Invalid Session”. This issue is normally because the client’s launcher failed to authenticate with Mojang’s session servers. Luckily, you can fix this error with just a few steps.</p>



<p>You may also be running a non-premium version of Minecraft. If you did not pay for Minecraft, you will not be allowed to join most servers due to the server running in online mode, however, it can be changed to offline mode fairly easily.</p>



<h2>How to resolve</h2>



<p>How to resolve on a premium server</p>



<ol><li>Close your game.</li><li>Log off your account from your launcher.</li><li>You will then be asked to type in your email and password again, please do.</li><li>Once logged in, you can then start your game and join the server.</li></ol>



<p>How to allow cracked players on your server</p>



<ol><li>Head to the Game Panel and stop the server.</li><li>To the left of the panel click “Config Files” and then click “Server Settings”.</li><li>Locate “Online Mode” and set it to disabled, then click save.</li><li>Head back to the Game Panel dashboard and turn the server back on. It should now let you join.</li></ol>



<h2>Common Issues</h2>



<p>After restarting the launcher, players still can’t join<br>If you are using premium Minecraft and have already followed the steps on to resolve the error and still cannot join, try restarting the server.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/minecraft-failed-to-verify-username-error-fix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to make a Bed in Minecraft</title>
		<link>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-make-a-bed-in-minecraft/</link>
					<comments>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-make-a-bed-in-minecraft/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[minevote.xyz@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bed in minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bed minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bed wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mincraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed ar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed designs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed meme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed save]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bed wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft beds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bedwars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft build hacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft bunk bed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft furniture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft hindi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft in hindi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft loft bed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft pe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft pocket edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minecraft youtuber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preston minecraft]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://minevote.xyz/blog/?p=22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How to make a Bed in Minecraft Overview So, you’re a Minecraft noob and you’re tired of digging yourself into a hidey-hole every night when the monsters come out. You hate having to wait until sunrise for the safety of a bright and shiny plain. Worry not, Minecraft noob! We got the thing for you: ... <a title="How to make a Bed in Minecraft" class="read-more" href="https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-make-a-bed-in-minecraft/" aria-label="More on How to make a Bed in Minecraft">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>How to make a Bed in Minecraft</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/12/17184700/bed-crafting-recipe.png" alt=""/></figure>



<h2>Overview</h2>



<p>So, you’re a Minecraft noob and you’re tired of digging yourself into a hidey-hole every night when the monsters come out. You hate having to wait until sunrise for the safety of a bright and shiny plain. Worry not, Minecraft noob! We got the thing for you: Beds. Brand spankin’ new (not really) technology brought straight from Mojang HQ that allows you to skip the night entirely, and set a new spawn point. That’s right. Today’s blog will go over beds in Minecraft. Everything, from how they work to the history that surrounds them, and maybe even their future. Let’s get started!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/12/17184712/bed.png" alt=""/></figure>



<h3>Shleep</h3>



<p>Beds are a fairly simple and well known part of Minecraft. They have a few uses, which include but are not limited to sleeping through the night and setting the player’s spawn point. To do this, the player needs to press the ‘use’ button (on Java Edition, this is RMB by default) on the bed. Beds do not work if monsters are within an 8-block radius horizontally. Beds also do not work if it is daytime. It must be either night, or a thunderstorm. After around five seconds of a sleeping animation, the world will turn to day, and you will jump out of bed.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/12/17184705/Phantoms.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p>As of 1.13, not sleeping for more than three days will result in the spawning of Phantoms at night. Phantoms are airborne hellspawn that exist solely to ruin your life. They will swoop in and slap you, quickly ascending back up to a safe elevation. The longer you go without sleep, the more that will spawn each night. Phantoms are player specific, so if you get a good night’s rest while your friends have insomnia, you should be left alone.</p>



<p>Beds naturally spawn in igloos, and some specific Village houses, but they can also be crafted for fairly cheap. All you need is&nbsp;3 wooden planks of any kind, and 3 matching wool. Make sure that you shear matching Sheep! When placed, Beds take up two blocks of space, so make some room in your crib!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn.apexminecrafthosting.com/img/uploads/2020/12/17184700/bed-crafting-recipe.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p>As for ‘occupied’ beds, players cannot use a bed in use by another player. However, if a Villager is sleeping in a bed, just kick that sucker out by using it! They’ll jump upright in respect for the superior combatant, you! It may be a bit mean, but it’s a tough world out there!</p>



<h3>Factoids and Trivia</h3>



<p>Here’s a list of random facts and functions about beds that won’t be helpful or necessary to know for most of you, but should be included in this blog nevertheless! I’m quite thorough, you know?</p>



<p>Bouncing&nbsp;– Landing on a bed will reduce fall damage by 50% and bounce you up for 66% of the impact velocity. Essentially, if you fall high you’ll bounce high too. Baby Villagers bounce on beds during the day.</p>



<p>What Fall Damage?&nbsp;– If a player falls a considerable height, and uses a bed before reaching the ground, the fall damage is not nullified but activated when they leave the bed. Yikes!</p>



<p>Spawn Points&nbsp;– Although the player cannot sleep in a bed during the day, using the bed still sets a new spawn point. Safety assured!</p>



<p>Friends&nbsp;– In Multiplayer, all server residents must sleep simultaneously for the day to pass. Otherwise, any player sleeping will sit in a perpetual slumber!</p>



<p>Waterlogged Beds&nbsp;– If a bed is waterlogged, meaning the bed has water sources registered on it, the player cannot sleep in it without the Water Breathing Effect, or Conduit Power.</p>



<p>Boom!&nbsp;– Beds cannot be slept in when placed in other dimensions, but you won’t just get a message. You’re in for a treat if you try this!</p>



<p>Take Care of Yourself&nbsp;– Players cannot sleep while on fire, poisoned, or starving. For good reason too, you got bigger problems!</p>



<p>The Colors&nbsp;– Originally, Beds only had one color. Red.</p>



<p>Culture?&nbsp;– Each type of Village has its own set of colored beds that spawn in their buildings. For Example, Savanna Villages only spawn with red or yellow beds.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Welp, that’s everything! You now know what you need to operate your bed. They aren’t that complex, as they’re an essential part of every Minecrafter’s playthroughs. All the way from noobs to pro, everyone has used a respawn point one time or another. Or, if you’re super advanced, you can use them as tools of mass destruction! Maybe don’t try that last part, but I implore you to get creative! With that said, I hope this pseudo guide helped you. Have a great day!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://minevote.xyz/blog/2021/01/17/how-to-make-a-bed-in-minecraft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
